Retreat! Retreat!
Not a trap!
Presence of humans, so many, did not account for.
Well now, I see you're quick to comprehend languages.
Alright, tell us, who are you exactly? Are you perhaps residents of the Golden City?
We are merely interference units. We are made to observe, touch, search, and gather.
New language. New outward appearances. We would like to learn more about you. We would like to gain information.
Oh, I get that. There's a ton we want to know as well. So why don't we talk it out, eh? Let's really get to know each other.
Eventually, we would come to find out that even if this truly was the Golden City, compared to our homelands that cast us aside, it was a far more harsh environment.
The only way back would be using this thing that got us here.
But how do we use it though?
Do we even know how to get it up and running again?
We have no choice but to try.
When we arrived at the Shoto region, the ritual site's altar just started running on its own, and we were able to descend.
We discovered it was due to a nearby hollow clutching a special stone.
I don't know why he was even there, but...
After we put him inside, the altar began to move.
It was necessary for us to test whether or not he could make the altar go back up.
It worked, and after a few hours, it came back down again.
What?
But sadly, we learned humans cannot return from this area and still maintain their human form.
Listen up, Wazukyan has a report.
Okay, everyone, the legendary Golden City does indeed exist.
It stretches out before us, untouched.
Yet we cannot go beyond it, nor can we return from it.
We find ourselves standing within a legend.
And we're the only ones who can find the truth of that legend.
We've already abandoned our homelands.
If we can't leave, we shall make a new beginning here.
We shall become the first citizens of the Golden City at the bottom of the world!
It is only in this miraculous place that one can achieve their greatest wish.
And as we found out...
We did not all need to be prophets touched by the Divine to believe these powers to be true.
How's it looking?
If we cut down on rations, they'll last about seven days.
But the water will probably go a bit faster.
I'm sure that interference unit knows where to find water.
I already asked. Securing the root is the main issue.
Since they are not living beings like we are, the curse doesn't affect them.
Which of course is the reason why they don't know how much one can ascend without triggering the deforming curse.
Well, yeah, that is a problem.
What's this? I wish we knew what it says.
Soikyu soishi, Metsukorijasu.
Oh, wait, you can read it?
Mine!
Extraordinary. It contains glyph strings unknown to us.
I would guess the literacy rate of their settlement must greatly surpass ours by far.
In order to comprehend the Golden City, it seems your knowledge will prove indispensable.
Oh, yeah, that's right. She told me what her name is. It's Idomyui. She's smart.
Fueko, listen. Gather everyone who can read and write. And the interference units.
Alright, Idomyui. We're counting on you.
So, Idomyui. Where do you think the residents of this place went?
Idomyui don't know, but they are not in village now.
My village legends tell stories of people with patterns on their bodies to say what they are.
We make homage.
When one reaches age in my village, we put patterned ink decorations on body meant to imitate the residents of Golden City.
But Idomyui's body cannot bear any child inside of it.
As part of shame, ink of sacrifice put on Idomyui.
What is this thing? How long has it been in here?
What's going on, you guys?
Fueko! There's something strange in this helmet!
When do you think it got in there?
Huh?
How adorable!
Idomyui! It might be dangerous!
Oh, wow. I guess it's super tame.
For a creature that lives inside a shell to hide, it sure lacks a sense of larryness.
Fueko, we cannot afford to keep that creature.
It'll be alright. Even docile creatures have managed to survive. They live here. And so, so can we.
If we study its way of life, then we can learn from it. It might just provide some sort of breakthrough to help us secure our survival.
Yeah.
I say we keep the thing here and observe it. If that's okay.
Why not? Besides, it's kinda cute.
I've identified some sources of water. There are five at the same level as us where the chance of being hit with the curse is low. Of those, the two larger bodies of water fall within the territory of dangerous creatures. And well, of the remaining three, one has a fallen iron tower in it, so rust has contaminated the water. And another is so hot even the interference units can't approach it.
That only leaves one option then.
Yes, but the interference units do not need water. So, it'll be up to us to determine whether or not the water is potable.
It looks clear. And it doesn't smell.
No, wait. We have to boil it. For now, let's just bring some back. Everyone's waiting.
Now we just need some food. Having a secured source of water, we finally had a foothold. Now we had to make sacrifices along the way. Little by little, we acquired the skills to stay alive in the brutal golden city.
What's wrong, Ida Mui? Are you alright?
Ida Mui, Ida Mui, I feel a little hot.
Ida Mui smells like mommy.
What? So is that the reason? Is that why in the beginning you felt attached to me?
Mommy's smell. The smell of mating with lots of people. Mommy's very important. So she has lots of children. But Ida Mui only girl child come from mommy. Only one to be born. So big brother's nice to Ida Mui. But when they examine Ida Mui insides, find out no have kids like mommy. They said that Ida Mui is cursed. Cursed one born of giant.
So must go back to giant pit, so must go back to giant pit where cursed one belongs. Mommy and big brother's not like hearing.
Ida Mui is cursed. Cursed one born of giant pit, so must go back to giant pit where cursed one belongs.
Mommy and big brother's not like hearing. Don't look at Ida Mui anymore after that. They... they said that Ida Mui... not child anymore. They said...
Ida Mui, uh, so you know, I can't have kids. And so I'm very sorry, but, uh, I... I can't exactly take the place of your mother.
No replacement for mommy. Ida Mui wants wiggles. Ida Mui don't want to be thrown away ever again.
At first, I had wanted to find the light. But in the end, the only thing I finally found waiting for me... was more darkness.
But what a... what a very warm darkness it was. Ida Mui, I will never let you go.
Ida Mui, Ida Mui...
Shhhh!
Oh!
Ida Mui!
Whee!
Blacko! Blacko!
You gotta get up! Come on!
Okay.
Ida Mui, wake up. It's morning.
Ida Mui?
Oh my gosh. Diarrhea?
Transparent egg casings? Caterpillars?
Weko, we need your help!
Everyone... just had a slight fever yesterday.
Look, something's really wrong with Aicham.
The toes look like lead that's been melted and hardened.
It looks like everyone else is getting sick too.
I-I'll need water to care for them.
Also, I think this might be contagious.
Okay, Vueko. They're in your hands now.
Understood.
We'll be back.
The fever won't go down.
Vueko!
What is it this time?
It's the food survey team.
Only these three were able to make it back and well...
They didn't last very long.
Why do they... look like that?
Achapoca, I'd like to collect a sample of this rock.
Do your thing.
It's not a rock.
Layers piled atop each other.
The corpse of a larger creature melted and solidified.
We've been tricking the stuff that caused that to happen.
So what do you want to do, Belov?
There's no other water for us to take back with us.
I know. We'll bring it back.
We do still need the water after all.
Though we will need to tell them.
Hey, Vueko.
This was inside his bag.
Any idea what it is?
Did our Prophet, touched by the Divine, have some kind of premonition?
I think it's some sort of relic.
Though I don't know what it's used for.
Huh.
Think that interference unit might know something?
Or did the supernatural power of the Great Pit sense our creation send it to us?
Either way, that was it.
That was the turning point.
The water itself is a living organism.
Those things in the feces were probably some kind of eggs or seeds.
But we... I mean, we even boiled it!
These guys here sure keep surprising us with their creative survival tactics.
And now, we no longer have a safe watering hole for us to source.
The only options that we're left with are to continue allowing this pseudo-water to ravage us and make us sick.
Or to reject it and die of unrelenting thirst.
Eating and drinking in this place has always been a challenge. But now we're in a truly tough spot.
The onset and symptoms differ from each person. We might find a way to combat it by examining everyone.
Times of the essence.
Can I just add one thing?
Where did you obtain?
I believe the food survey team that brought this back went around to all the traps we set.
Do you have any idea where they might have come across it?
Do not know.
Those kids were still alive and in relatively good shape when they first got here.
Does this relic perhaps have something to do with all this?
Indeed. It is responsible.
Round relics are the shape of wishes.
Some are modest. Some are strong, like this one.
Wait, Wishes? What kind of wish made them like that?
Incorrect. Not just any kind of wish. That is Cradle of Desire. To put it in your way of speaking, it is wish-granting egg.
You should not touch directly. If you are consumed, your wish will dissipate.
Adult humans are diverse and complex. They are not suited. If you wish to make use of it, a juvenile is best.
Not good. They need to drink water. But this water ravages their bodies.
It hurts, Wiko. It hurts.
It hurts.
What's wrong?
Your hand. Does it hurt? Turn back to normal, please!
You mean that wish-granting egg?
Even if adults can't, it should work for a child to use, won't it?
Fear felt by a juvenile is much closer to origin. The probability is very high.
Give it a try.
We have too many worldly thoughts. Let's bet on that kid's wish.
Wazukyan, why isn't Belov here?
He's finally fallen ill as well. Trying to be brave.
He's sick?
We don't have much time left to spare. I'm counting on you, Vueko.
Have faith now. I know that kid will be our salvation.
We have been forced into disgrace and expelled. We have had our home taken from us, and our descendants.
Irum Yui is the baby sister of those descendants. There is a hand that could save us, but if we do not reach out, we'll once again lose our place to belong.
I beg you. Get better.
Wazukyan said that he knew the kid would be our salvation.
It was the first time I'd seen him close up. The face of a divinely possessed prophet.
I feel so, so hungry.
Vueko! Vueko!
Vueko!
But you're...
Adam Yui, you.
Look at me, Vueko. It doesn't hurt at all.
Mom!
Adam Yui, come this way.
Even though she's full of energy, and she says her hand doesn't hurt,
obviously something's not quite right.
I wonder what the child wishes for to heal like that.
The thing is, she doesn't seem to remember.
Hey, if you keep messing with it, it'll start hurting.
It doesn't hurt!
What do you think?
Why don't we leave this to Vueko?
We'll devote ourselves to acting as support.
She has the most earnest emotional bond that any of us with Ida Mui.
I'd like to believe that Ida Mui's wish is somehow related to that as well.
We were near our breaking point. There were very few of us left. And those who could still walk were dropping day by day. If I were to fall ill as well, Ida Mui would be left here all on her own.
Ida Mui, are you awake?
Vueko?
Ida Mui!
You're changing! How are you feeling today?
I'm just fine.
Why Vueko? Why sad looking?
It's nothing. I'm just confused. I have to ask you, Ida Mui. Don't you ever get sad sometimes?
You're here Vueko, so it's fine.
You know, they say that your body is trying to change into the body you wish you always had, Ida Mui.
Huh?
All I could do was pray that the choice I made wasn't the wrong one.
With this wish-granting egg, did Ida Mui perhaps wish for her own happiness? For her own fears to vanish?
Wait a minute for her.
Ida mui!
lobby to hang two together!
For her to hit, bow your head was tired for the encouragement.
Where are you?
ices?
Meagie!
Why are you screaming?!
Vueko, do you see?
A baby?!
I didn't know how to react.
I didn't know what to?
Okay, Iram Yui, there's still some of the film left on its face.
Okay, now clean it off gently.
The next day, the baby took its last breath.
It didn't have any sort of organ for ingesting food, so it could neither eat nor drink.
It just languished in Iram Yui's arms.
Was this... was this what she wished for?
Either way, it was coming true.
A second has been born to Iram Yui.
Was this really what she wanted?
Her second, and third, and even the ones after that, were born only to die.
She never escaped the sorrow of her wish continually taken from her.
How long could she last?
My stomach burns.
Diarrhea.
Looks like it's finally my turn.
I can't move.
I want water.
So badly.
All I could think about is water.
Grant that child's wish.
You are the only one who can do it.
That smell.
Food.
What a...
What a tempting aroma.
Hurry.
Hurry and give it to me.
Um...
Who knew...
Who knew anything could be so delicious?
Here.
Slowly now.
Mm-hmm.
Something so...
So very simple.
Something more...
Uh...
Wasu-kyan.
Good morning.
Really does work wonders, doesn't it?
That was...
Uh...
It, um...
It was...
Everything's fine.
Uh...
I gave everybody else some, too.
I told you, didn't I?
That kid saved everyone.
Thank you.